it's snowing outside it's cold but in
business Central the marketing
department are dreaming
big they want to have a special themed
version of the sales quote for the
holidays so what they want is send out
quotes that look like this pixel
pixelated snowflakes maybe a snowman
instead of the wouldn't say boring but
but at least say blue sales quote design
that we always use so in this video I'm
going to show you how the department the
marketing department can do just this in
a few minutes with no need for a
developer the first thing is going to
the report layouts page this is where
all the layouts for for reports are
hiding in business Central and here you
can see if uh if you search for
themeable uh in um in version 2024
release Wave 2 we added what we call
themeable layouts you can see there's
themeable here in the name and for sales
quote sales confirmation invoice and so
on uh we have added these themeable
layouts what uh what are these well let
me just search or sorry filter to the
quote we want to do quotes sales quote
here and I'll just save this view
here sorry let's do that again
1304 filter to to standard quote save
this as quotes you don't have to but I
just want to go back to these to show it
again and uh here you have the blue
themable quote if we just run the report
with this just pick tray research as a
customer and preview you can see
yeah it's a sales quote design nothing
fancy but just a wait and
see if we export this layout and open it
in word this is a a word layout and
enable editing you you notice that if
you choose design and themes this layout
is responsive to the different office
themes so the look and feel the fonts
the colors you can just change change
them right away like this now the in the
marketing department we wanted a snow uh
so something dark in uh in in color and
uh we like this this is by the way also
the the new abts font in office that
also came is is available in business
Central online as of December
2024 so this is nice but we also want a
watermark so here under Des sign we have
a under the page background menu we have
a watermark uh
place a way to place watermarks and we
want some snowflakes we want pixelated
snowflakes and the best way to generate
these is of course in paint so here in
paint I have um taken the image Creator
and given
it a prompt snowfalling I've chosen
pixel art as the style and then I have
chosen create this after 10 seconds gave
me a number of variants for for this and
I think I actually like this version so
I'll will crop this and save it to my
download folder so I can use it as a
watermark so back in word if I go to
Watermark and custom watermarks here and
I choose picture and select picture
let's see if we can find our picture
from that was downloaded here and let's
take snow pixels that was the one I
generated and I choose apply and there
you go so now we have a watermark I will
save this layout and then go back to
business Central and upload it as a new
layout so I choose here on report
layouts I'm have chosen the right report
so I choose new and let me just say Let
It
Snow and I choose format option of word
choose okay and then I need to upload
the layout this was the one I just um
edited so after a few seconds my let it
know is ready I can test it with the
same try research customer and
preview
and there you go now we have completely
changed our sales quote no need for a
developer and we can choose this as a
default layout for December or January
and then when we get to another season
we can simply add a new season layout
for our quotes that's it guys hope you
will go and do some awesome layouts for
Christmas thank you